Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Motion Picture Films
Hoover Institution Archives
- Latviesu Centrala Komiteja records, 1940s; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf4g5003f5 (Box 48017: Film Shelf)
  Films depict scenes of life in displaced person camps in Germany. (4 16mm films)
- Le Temps des doryphores motion picture film, 1940-1944; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1f59r366 (Box 78009: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films in the collection depict aspects of social and political conditions in German-occupied France, 1940-1944, including scenes of leading German political and military figures, German armed forces, and daily life in French towns and villages. (5 16mm films)
- Lindgren-Utsi (Ethel J) papers, 1924-1944; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf1779n4qf (Box 79007: Film Shelf)
  The film in this collection is about domesticated reindeer in Manchuria. (1 16mm film)
- Lodge (John Davis) papers, 1969-1973; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/ft9c6007r1 (Box 86005: Boxes 317-319)
  Collection contains incremental motion picture film of John Davis Lodge performing ambassadorial functions in Argentina from 1969-1973, and other functions. (13 16mm films)
- Loewenthal (Alfred Max) papers, 1886-1980; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4v19r7f9 (Box 80189: Box 59)
- Lowman (Myers G) papers, 1957, 1960; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3d5n999w (Box 67019: Film Shelf)
  Films relating to the civil rights movement and anti-communism. (4 16mm films)
- McCloskey (Paul N) papers, 1970; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1s20243r (Box 82112: Box 450)
  Collection includes an episode of"Face the Nation". (1 16mm film)
- Meese (Edwin) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt358035d1 (Box 91005: Film Shelf)
  Films in this collection are Ronald Reagan's public service announcement about being prepared for disasters. (2 16mm films)
- Merland (Mildred) motion picture film 1929, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5t1nf17c (Box 79023: Film Shelf)
  Films depict the state burial of Sun Yat-sen, president of China, in Nanking. (2 16mm films)
- Mikolajczyk (Stanislaw) papers, 1940; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf658004nd (Box 78111: Box 204)
  Films in the collection relate to communism in Eastern Europe and Poland, agriculture in Poland, Polish politics, especially during World War II, Polish-Soviet relations, the International Peasant Union, the Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe, and Polish emigre politics. (1 35mm, 16mm films)
- Miller (William P.) papers, 1943-1974; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9d5nf29h (Box 77074: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film in collection relates to the United States Army Signal Corps operations in North Africa, Germany, Italy and France during World War II. (5 16mm films)
  "Use copies of motion pictures in this collection are available for immediate access. "Moulay Idriss, Khenifra - Use copy reference number: 77074_f_0010696. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MZCX1OoBbVc
  "Casablanca, Marrakech, Meknes." Use copy reference number: 77074_f_0010692. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yfQx30AjgOc
  "Africa, Algeria, Corsica, St. Tropez, Toulon." Use copy reference number: 77074_f_0010694. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BWyd-K4V5rc
  "Germany." Use copy reference number: 77074_f_0010687. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8mku5TR7P3k
  "Germany, Austria." Use copy reference number: 77074_f_0010684. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6UQ7qv1TTkg
- Monday (Mark) papers, 1961-1984; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf4s2003jp (Box 74063: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to the Minutemen and other right-wing paramilitary groups in the U.S., and to the Irish republican movement in Northern Ireland. (3 16mm films)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference number: 74063_f_0001046.
- My home, my prison audiovisual materials, 1990-1992; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5n39r87p (Box 2002C81: Film Shelf)
  Raw footage relates to the Palestinian activist Raymonda Hawa Tawil. (521 16mm films)
- National Broadcasting Company, Inc. audiovisual material, 1958-1989; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf6m3nb1jb (Box 64003: Film Shelf)
  Films pertaining to Cuba, Bay of Pigs Invasion, and Cuban Missile Crisis. (110 16mm films)
- Neizvestnyi (Ernest) motion picture film, circa 1977; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt2j49r6mt (Box 80110: Film Shelf)
  Films depict Ernest I. Neizvestnyi at work in his studio, and his works in public places in the Soviet Union. (2 16mm films)
- Nicolaevsky (Boris I) collection, 1960; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf7290056t (Box 63013: Film Shelf)
  Film depicts the 80th birthday celebration for Rafail Abramovich in New York. (1 8mm films)
- Nofziger (Lyn) papers, 1980; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt438nf37f (Box 2010C32: Film Shelf)
  Film in the collection is a documentary short narrated by James Stewart and focusing on Pat Nixon's contributions as First Lady of the United States. (1 16mm film)
- Olney (Warren) motion picture film, 1936; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6000348n (Box 66025: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film of ceremonies held in Hindenburg Park in Los Angeles on German Day, 1936; and of interviews of Dr. Salin, a criminologist, and W. Olney III, United States assistant attorney general, 1953-1957, relating to the incidence of crime in the United States. (2 16mm films)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access: http://archive.org/details/csth_000032
- Pacific Gas and Electric Company Program Series, 1960-1970; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf5v19n7v4 (Box 80177: Film Shelf)
  Sound recordings and motion picture film of a series of political education programs, featuring campaign presentations by candidates for election to major state political offices in California. (33 16mm films)
  Use copies of some motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access: Joe Eley lecture about the history of Fabianism circa 1962 https://archive.org/details/csth_000061
  "Politics 1962: Glenn M. Anderson, Democratic candidate for lieutenant governor, California 1962" https://archive.org/details/csth_000052
  "Politics 1962: Edmund G. Brown, Democratic candidate for governor, California 1962" https://archive.org/details/csth_000054
  "Politics 1962: George Christopher, Republican candidate for lieutenant governor, California 1962" https://archive.org/details/csth_000066
  "Politics 1962: Tom Coakley, Republican candidate for attorney general, California 1962" https://archive.org/details/csth_000063
  "Politics 1962: Stanley Mosk, Democratic candidate for attorney general, California 1962" https://archive.org/details/csth_000062
  "Politics 1962: Richard Richards, Democratic candidate for US Senate October 9, 1962" https://archive.org/details/csth_000064
  "Politics 1964: Election Post-Mortem 1964" https://archive.org/details/csth_000068
  "Politics 1966: Houston I. Flournoy, candidate for controller, California 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000056
  "Politics 1966: Alan Cranston, candidate for controller, California October 4, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000057
  "Politics 1966: Thomas C. Lynch, candidate for attorney general, California October 6, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000058
  "Politics 1966: Robert H. Finch, candidate for lieutenant governor, California October 18, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000059
  "Politics 1966: Glenn M. Anderson, candidate for lieutenant governor, California October 20, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000053
  "Politics 1966: Edmund G. Brown, candidate for governor, California November 2, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000055
  "Politics 1966: Ronald Reagan, candidate for governor, California November 3, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000060
  "Politics 1966: Election Post-Mortem November 15, 1966" https://archive.org/details/csth_000051
- Pash (Boris T) papers, 1936-1945; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf300002fn (Box 72033: Film Shelf)
  Films in the collection include various types of footage From Europe from before and during World War II. (46 16mm, 8mm films)
  "Alsos Mission Reel reel 1." Use copy reference number: 72033_f_0002488_r02_pt01.
  "Alsos Mission reel 2." Use copy reference number: 72033_f_0002488_r02_pt02.
  "Alsos Mission Reel 3." Use copy reference number: 72033_f_0002488_r02_pt03.
  "Alsos Mission reel 4." Use copy reference number: 72033_f_0002488_r02_pt04.
- Pasternak Family papers, 1960; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf70000535 (Box 96063: Film Shelf)
- Pauker (Guy J) papers, 1959; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3b69n68z (Box 82096: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film includes interview of Sukarno. (1 16mm film)
- Person to Person Films records, 1984-1988; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5r29q26g (Box 2000C24: Film Shelf)
  Raw footage and recorded sound which was to be contained in a documentary relating to civil war in Nicaragua. (678 16mm films)
- Peterkin (Wilbur J) papers, 1943-1994; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9n39r8v7 (Box 76018: Film Shelf)
  Collection includes motion picture film of footage from China during World War II. (8 16mm films)
  "China U.S.A.O.S., 1944-1945." Use copy reference number: 76018_f_0008113.
  "Dixie Compound, Roll 4 circa 1944-1945." Use copy reference number: 76018_f_0008799.
  "Mission to Yenan, Roll 5 circa 1944-1945." Use copy reference number: 76018_f_0008114.
- Polish Arts and Culture Foundation, 1933-1988; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1n39r47h (Box 2001C55: Boxes 42-53, Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to Polish culture and history, and to the Polish community in the United States. (115 16mm, 35mm films)
- Pomian (Andrzej) papers, 1943; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5j49s12h (Box 2009C45: Film Shelf)
  The films in the collection consist of war footage. (13 35mm films)
  "Polish Bombers' Holiday." Use copy reference number: 2009c45_f_0010675.
- Pronin (Alexander and Ethel) collection, 1908-1991; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt138nd1k8 (Box 91052: Film Shelf)
  Film collection relates to aspects of Russian and Soviet culture and history. (386 16mm films)
- Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1955-1969; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4489q9wz (Box 2000C71: Box 126, Boxes 2164-2169, Boxes 2221-2222, Box 18400, Film Shelf)
  Collection contains promotional films about Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty. (65 16mm films)
  "Your Crusade for Freedom." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011964.
  "Hungarians Uprising 1956." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_v_0011962.
  "The Most Incredible Challenge." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011965.
  "How Your Truth Dollars Fight for Freedom." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0007265.
  "Margin for Victory." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011961.
  "Newspaper." Use copy reference number: 2007C71_f_0011961.
  "Student." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011961.
  "Cafe." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011961.
  "This is Radio Free Europe." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0007268.
  "Window to the West." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011963.
  "Freedom Arsenal of Truth." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0007264.
  "Towers of Truth." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011964.
  "Lifeline to Freedom." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0008803.
  "Towers of Truth, Crusade for Freedom." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011964.
  "A World Away." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0007264.
  "Tolstoy." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0007264.
  "Taipai." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0008802.
  "Antennas and Wires." Use copy reference number: 2000c71_f_0008802.
  "Vectorscope test + contors equipment." Use copy reference number: 2000c71_f_0008802.
  "1958-1959 Munich Trip." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0007264.
  "This is Radio Liberty." Use copy reference number: 2000C71_f_0011966.
- Ray (Dixy L) papers, 1937-1982; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3199n5v9 (Box 82106: Film Shelf)
  Collection has 15 films on scientific matters dating from Dixy Lee Ray's years at the Pacific Science Center and 1 film on the economic impact of the eruption of Mount St. Helens. (16 16mm films)
- Red Myth: Motion Picture Film, 1961; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf2g50023w (Box 61005: Film Shelf)
  The film talks about the history of communism. (13 16mm films)
- Right to Believe motion picture film, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt2w103278 (Box 83005: Film Shelf)
  Film relates to religion in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe. (1 16mm film)
- Round Eyes in the Middle Kingdom, 1995; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9m3nf3w3 (Box 2003C62: Film Shelf)
  Raw footage relating to Europeans in China. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion pictures in this collection are available for immediate access.
  Use copy reference numbers: 2003c62_f_0012443.
- Rozek (Edward J.), undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8jq14b7 (Box 2014C58: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to political freedom. (3 16mm films)
- Russia's Five Year Plan motion picture film, 1928-1932; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt0779r47k (Box 77089: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film relates to the first five-year plan between 1928-1932. (2 16mm films)
- Saga of a Superliner motion picture film, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6p3040fs (Box 81038: Film Shelf)
  Documentary film of the ocean liner"Queen Elizabeth". (1 16mm film)
- Scheinman (William X) papers, 1959; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt0k4033gs (Box 98036: Box 57)
  Film in collection contains interview with Kenyan political leader Tom Mboya. (1 16mm film)
- Schenck (Hubert G) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf538nb0b5 (Box 50007: Film Shelf)
- Schmidt (Harry) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf4f59n6t6 (Box 68033: Film Shelf)
  Film about Iwo Jima. (1 16mm film)
- Short (Walter Campbell) papers, 1941; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt687034m7 (Box 75012: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor. (3 16mm films)
- Should the Allies Trade With Communists? Motion picture film, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt3r29r5vk/ (Box 80002: Film Shelf)
  Film relates to Soviet-American trade. (1 16mm film)
- Shoup (David M) papers, 1927-1971; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf238n98jr (Box 76027: Film Shelf)
  Motion pictures relate to the Tarawa campaign, other World War II campaigns in the Pacific Theater, postwar activities of the Marine Corps, service as the Commandant of the Marine Corps, and the Vietnam War. (9 16mm films)
- Silvey (Jack, collector) Motion Picture Film 1943-1945, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3779n5z5 (Box 83006: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film collection depicts miscellaneous American military operations during World War II. (7 16mm films)
- Solzhenitsyn (Aleksandr Isaevich) speeches and writings, 1975-1982; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt0g5030zx (Box 76033: Film Shelf)
  The film in this collection is about Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn. (1 16mm film)
- Song Feiqing papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c80z73wq (Box 85067: Film Shelf)
- Soviet Union. Gosudarstvennyi komitet po kinematografii motion picture film, 1972-1976; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt1t1nd81z (Box 93065: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to the role of the Soviet armed forces during World War II and subsequently. (51 16mm films)
- Spitzer (Robert R) papers, 1954-1994; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf1580014n (Box 85007: Film Shelf)
  Films pertain to world food supply and United States politics. (2 16mm films)
- Spunt (Georges) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt5p3033qm (Box 97072: Film Shelf)
  Films relate to social conditions and the European community in Shanghai from the 1910s through the 1940s. (4 16mm films)
- Stanford University 50th anniversary celebration motion picture film, 1941; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4x0nf0vj (Box 95026: Film Shelf)
  Film depicts Herbert Hoover, Ray Lyman Wilbur and others speaking at the commemoration of the fiftieth anniversary of the founding of Stanford University. (1 16mm film)
  Use copies of motion picture films in this collection are available for immediate access: http://archive.org/details/csth_00007
- Stuart (Charles E) papers, 1926-1936; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf596nb0h2 (Box 80067: Film Shelf)
  Collection includes motion picture film of social conditions and economic activities in the Soviet Union from 1926-1936. (68 16mm, 35mm films)
  "Soviet Russia Through the Eyes of an American." Use copy reference number: 80067_f_0007472. http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pk2DJTAmwJ8
- Tarsaidze (Alexandre G) papers, 1944-1977; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3b69n65d (Box 78055: Film Shelf)
  The collection contains films related to the British royal family as well as the Russian Imperial Family. (17 35mm, 16mm films)
- Teller (Edward) papers, 1955-1966; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf6x0nb1wg (Box 76074: Film Shelf)
  Films in the collection show television appearances and talks by Edward Teller. (8 16mm films)
- Todd (Oliver J) papers, 1927-1932; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf896nb2wn (Box 73087: Box 63)
  Home movies from the 1920s and 1930s in China. (10 35mm, 16mm films)
- Truth About Communism motion picture film, 1962; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt9p3037cm (Box 86092: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to international communism. (3 16mm films)
- UFA motion picture newsreels, 1933-1945; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt758036qd (Box 48007: Film Shelf)
  The collection shows German military operations and conditions in Germany during World War II, mainly during the 1939-1942 period as well as a few pre-war newsreels of Nazi leaders and rallies. (450 16mm, 35mm films)
- United Nations Association of the United States of America. San Francisco Chapter records, 1945-1970; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt229032q8 (Box 77024: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture films relate to the operations of United Nations organizations, world politics, and international human rights. (74 16mm, (1) 35mm films)
- United States. Army. Signal Corps pictorial matter, 1917-1919; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6z09s0j6 (Box 50012: Film Shelf)
  Film footage in collection shows American Operations in Europe during World War I. (3 16mm films)
- Universal Newspaper Newsreel motion picture film, 1931-1932; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt8w103651 (Box 85073: Film Shelf)
  The film depicts Japanese intervention in China. It Includes scenes of the bombing of Shanghai and of other events in Shanghai. (2 16mm, Mag Track films)
  Use copies of motion pictures in this collection are available for immediate access. Use copy reference numbers: 85073_f_0012442.
- Walter (Alonzo J., Jr) motion Picture Film, 1938-1943, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3r29n6bm (Box 80023: Film Shelf)
  The films depict German military and aerial operations, and German political leaders during World War II. (19 35mm films)
  "The Crossing of the Rhine River and Conquest of the Maginot Line." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001019.
  "German paratroopers." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001035.
  "German invasion of Crete." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0000988.
  "Danzig is German again." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001038.
  "In the Fuhrer's headquarters." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001037.
  "Uncle Daniel; Ruins at Dortmund; Hitler and Goering at 'Hero-Remembering Day,' Munich, 1943 November." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001032.
  "The German west boundary." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001039. "A battery goes into position." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001033.
  "Decision on the Balkan peninsula I: advance from all sides." Use copy reference number: 80023_f_0001040.
  "Invasion of France; Hitler accepts French surrender." 80023_f_0001036.
  "Aircraft at the Berlin airport." 80023_f_0000987.
  "Austria returns home 13 March 1938/the Fuhrer in Italy 3-9 May 1938." 80023_f_0001016.
  "The trip home: the Europa on the high seas." 80023_f_0001017.
  "Soldiers build a pontoon bridge." 80023_f_0001041.
  "The crossing of the Rhine River and conquest of the Maginot Line / Breaching the Maginot Line; Advancing in France; at sea; Hitler at memorial in Munich, 1940 November 23." 80023_f_0002141.
  "German mountain troops in the Caucasus; FW-200 bombers attack ships in the Atlantic." 80023_f_0001018."
- Wanda Roehr Foundation motion picture film 1939, http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt7q2nf3nh (Box 73093: Film Shelf)
  Film depicts the effects of the German bombing of Warsaw in September, 1939. (1 35mm film)
- Warsaw Uprising motion picture film, 1944; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt2199r5hh (Box 80096: Film Shelf)
  The film relates to the German occupation of Warsaw during World War II, and to the Warsaw uprising of 1944. (1 16mm film)
- Waste (James) collection, 1924; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8cz39dt (Box 2014C34: Film Shelf)
  Motion picture film in collection shows relief efforts in Armenia, circa 1917, and of the 1924 Olympic Games. (1 9.5mm films)
- We Supported Our Men in Vietnam, Inc., 1965-1995; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt596nf2hq (Box 93057: Film Shelf)
  Footage in the collection contains Public Service Announcement and footage of the organization's parade. (7 16mm films)
  "Flag Day Ceremony-Yankee Stadium June 14, 1967." Use copy reference number: 93057_f_0011995_r01.
  "Support Our Men in Vietnam Parade on Fifth Ave in New York City-30 min. version." Use copy reference number: 93057_f_0011997_r01.
- Wedemeyer (Albert C) papers, 1964; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf3x0n99pv (Box 83007: Film Shelf)
  Films in the collection pertain to Barry Goldwater and his 1964 United States presidential campaign. (2 16mm films)
- Weidner (John Henry) papers, undated; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/c8kd2194 (Box 2013C34: Film Shelf)
  Collection contains mostly Unidentified. films, but one film shows the visit of Queen Juliana of the Netherlands. (114 16mm films)
- West (Arthur L) papers, 1966-1967; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt6p30401k (Box 84023: Film Shelf)
  The film shows combat footage from the Vietnam War. (1 16mm film)
- Wheeler (Raymond A) papers, 1956-1957; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/tf9j49p054 (Box 78062: Film Shelf)
  Films relating to General Raymond Albert Wheeler and the U.S. Army Engineers. (5 16mm films)
- Whiting (Charles Jonathan) papers, 1937-1940; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt4j49r7fb (Box 74100: Box 9)
  Collection contains various films of Charles Jonathan Whiting's travels and locations he was stationed in and other unidentified films. (15 16mm films)
- Willis (Benjamin C) papers, 1921-1982; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt3290331q (Box 82064: Box 36, Box 51, Box 74)
  Films about Benjamin Coppage Willis, the superintendent of Chicago schools from 1953 to 1969. (4 8mm films)
- Winbigler (H. Donald) motion picture film collection, 1942-1943; http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/kt338nf002 (Box 87065: Film Shelf)